<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>eda on Asti&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>/categories/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in eda on Asti&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC by Attribution</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost beware</title>
      <link>/post/boost-beware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/boost-beware/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of new small-form factor, low part count boost converters being released for battery boost applications. These typically switch at high frequencies to reduce component sizes.
The Symptoms  Devices sometimes brownout with no pattern Heisenbugs Weird disconnections and readings  Possible Causes   Long path between output caps and output pin - these could act as parasitic inductances, causing output spikes when load changes
  High impedance path between IC ground and output ground - this should be obvious, but is most often overlooked because of layout constraints</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasheet to symbol</title>
      <link>/post/fast-part-altium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fast-part-altium/</guid>
      <description>Don&#39;t want to spend 20 minutes copy-pasting bits and pieces of the datasheet into a schematic symbol? This is for you.
Step 1 Open the datasheet PDF in a word processor. See image.
T	his is optional, but highly recommended, because PDFs don&#39;t have a flowing layout, and it is important that we have flow in this situation. If you&#39;re using a web datasheet, you can skip this step. You could also use something like Tabula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create high quality renders of your Altium boards</title>
      <link>/post/render-altium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/render-altium/</guid>
      <description>Create a realistic model Although this should be very straightforward, and while the 3D view in Altium is very accurate, getting it out of there is an entirely different story.
Step 1 This is, as you&#39;d expect to export a STEP file from Altium.
Use File &amp;gt; Export &amp;gt; STEP 3D
  Remember to export all 3D bodies as well. But you get no traces, silkscreen or pads in a STEP file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daisy chains in Altium</title>
      <link>/post/daisychain-altium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/daisychain-altium/</guid>
      <description>Why a way to daisy-chain? If you wanted to daisy chain any component the conventional way, say a bunch of WS2812s on your board, you&#39;d be making multiple instances and manually wiring them to each other.
  Steps  Make a sub-sheet out of the components you want to daisy chain (unless it&#39;s not in one already). Change the designator of the sheet to Repeat(name, 1, N) where N is the number of items you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combine your Bill of Materials</title>
      <link>/post/bom-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bom-merge/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you have a small run of boards, and you need to combine the BOM for them, to know how much to order or check against your inventory. This is especially needed when a lot of designs share parts, and it is tedious to combine them by hand.
Get csv-merge
Step 1 Export your BOM files as CSV (Comma Separated Values).
Check if most of your BOMs have the same header - the order does not matter, just the name.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>